We're going to start with the eye on the seventh day.
7日目の目から始めましょう。
We are in embryology.
私たちは発生学の中にいます。
And it's funny because I think, well, it's funny, it almost looks like an eye.
そして、おかしいな、これはおかしいな、ほとんど目のようだ、と私は思います。
Especially on the eighth day, it's a bit like an eye.
特に8日目は、少し目のようです。
But what's quite interesting is, what appears on the eighth day?
しかし、かなり興味深いのは、8日目に何が現れるかということです。
A small cavity appears, which we call the amniotic cavity.
羊膜腔と呼ばれる小さな腔が現れます。
This amniotic cavity is fundamental.
この羊膜腔は非常に重要です。
The eye, it comes from the brain.
目は脳から来ています。
in fact from the diencephalon, or more specifically, it is an expansion of the third
実際には間脳から、より具体的には、第三脳室の拡張です。
ventricle.
脳室。
But at some point, the neural system will receive primitive amniotic fluid.
しかし、ある時点で、神経系は原始的な羊水を受け取ります。
primitive.
原始的な。
This primitive amniotic fluid will form what we call CSF. So
この原始的な羊水は、LCRと呼ばれるものを形成します。したがって、
your first
あなたの最初の
CSF is amniotic fluid. It will enclose the fluid in the neural tube,
LCRは羊水です。それは液体を神経管の中に閉じ込めます。
neural tube, and then poof,
神経管の中に閉じ込め、そして、
growth, we will see, of this tube.
この管の成長が見られます。
which will open towards space, towards the front,
それは空間に向かって、前方に向かって開きます。
which will form these primitive vesicles.
それは原始的な小胞を形成します。
But in fact, it's a bubble
しかし実際には、それは泡です。
that inflates.
膨らむ。
Of air.
空気の。
But where is the remnant of this amniotic cavity?
しかし、この羊膜腔の痕跡はどこにあるのでしょうか？
It's what we call the pocket of bones.
それは骨の袋と呼ばれるものです。
We call that zone B.
私たちはそれをゾーンBと呼びます。
An individual.
個人。
And inside, you have...
そしてその中には、
cerebrospinal fluid.
脳脊髄液があります。
In the compartments,
コンパートメント内、
in lateral ventricles, etc.
側脳室など。
But outside of you,
しかし、あなたの外側には、
you have,
あなたは持っています、
in embryology,
発生学では、
what we call another fluid
別の液体と呼ばれるものがあります。
which is amniotic fluid.
それは羊水です。
This fluid that is inside here
ここにあるこの液体
and which is outside here,
そしてここにある外側の液体は、
it's the same fluid.
同じ液体です。
The eye, which is here, is a membrane, constantly seeking
ここにある目は膜であり、常にゾーンBのバランスを取ろうとします。
to balance zone B.
常にゾーンBのバランスを取ろうとします。
Zone B means that if you look at me, we will consider that my axis, my
ゾーンBとは、私を見ていただければ、私の軸、私の
physical body,
肉体は、
from my central line, would be my zone A.
私の中心線から、ゾーンAと見なされます。
And around me, I have what we call this amniotic cavity that starts here.
そして私の周りには、この
amniotic cavity that starts here.
羊膜腔と呼ばれるものがあります。
Look where it starts, eighth day, that's when we enter the mucosa.
それがどこから始まるか見てください。8日目、それは私たちが粘膜に入る瞬間です。
There is a loss of central fluid, an exudate,
中心液の喪失、滲出液があり、
which will form a small cavity.
それが小さな空洞を形成します。
And when this small cavity appears, I will have my ectoderm that will
そして、この小さな空洞が現れると同時に、私の外胚葉が
be put in place,
配置され、
what is called at this stage the epiblast.
この段階ではエピブラストと呼ばれます。
But that means that already here, it's the whole subtle structure.
しかし、それはすでにここに、目、脳を形成するすべての微妙な構造があることを意味します。
that will form the eye, that will form the brain.
目、脳を形成するすべての微妙な構造があることを意味します。
And at the same time, this amniotic cavity.
そして同時に、この羊膜腔。
Then, this amniotic cavity, look what it will become.
次に、この羊膜腔がどうなるか見てください。
A huge pocket that surrounded you for nine
9ヶ月間あなたを囲んでいた巨大な袋ですが、
months,
ヶ月間、
but which is no longer liquid now,
しかし、それはもはや液体ではなく、
but which is vaporous around you.
あなたの周りに蒸気のように漂っています。
So around us, we have this space,
だから私たちの周りにはこの空間があり、
we have this protection, and which must be in fact...
この保護があり、それは実際には...
in balance with your
あなたの
own internal fluid. Sometimes,
内側の液体とバランスが取れている必要があります。時には、
it's out of balance. Sometimes,
それは不均衡です。時には、
it's advanced. There are people, they are
それは進んでいます。人々の中には、
in rotation.
回転している人もいます。
Any accident, any whiplash, is an imbalance
すべての事故、すべてのむち打ちは、このレベルの不均衡です。
at that level. So, the eye,
このレベルの不均衡です。したがって、目は、
it's a balance
それはあなたの
between the depth of your
液体の深さ、あなたの神経系の深さ、
fluid, of your nervous system,
あなたの神経系の深さ、
which is the CSF,
LCRである、
which is fundamental,
それは根本的であり、
and also the space
そしてあなたの周りの
that is around you.
空間とのバランスです。
That's why just observing the position of the eyes,
だから、目の位置を観察するだけで、
just observing how the eye will position itself in space,
目が空間でどのように位置するかを観察するだけで、
it shows you how you are interfering with what is around you.
それはあなたがあなたの周りのものとどのように干渉しているかを示しています。
We already see if you have this balance and you will learn to observe the eyes,
このバランスがあるかどうかはすでにわかりますし、目を観察することを学ぶでしょう。
we all have a different eye, we all have an eye that is a little forward
私たちは皆異なる目をしており、私たちは皆少し前に出た目をしています。
because it is also related to the architecture of your brain,
それはあなたの脳の構造にも関係しているからです。
the best balance for you.
あなたにとって最高のバランスです。
mediastinum, we seek
縦隔、私たちは探しています
to have a
を持つために
horizontality in relation
水平性に関して
to a verticality. I have a
垂直性へ。私は持っています
horizontality in relation to my verticality
私の垂直性に対する水平性
in a mediastinal listening
縦隔聴診において
which is in a left
それは側方性にある
laterality. So
左。だから
my whole body here goes to the left
私の体全体が左に行きます
and I'm looking for myself here.
そして私はここで自分自身を探しています。
And so I'm looking for my horizontality
だから私は自分の水平性を探しています
in relation to my system
私の消化器系に関して
digestive, in relation to my peritoneal
私の腹膜系に関して。
peritoneal system.
腹膜。
always seeking this balance.
常にこのバランスを追求します。
So the manifestation of how the eye will position itself,
したがって、目がどのように配置されるかの現れは、
that's the best answer you can get.
それはあなたが持つことができる最良の応答にすぎません。
That's why it's very important to observe the eyes after treatment.
だからこそ、治療後に目を観察することが非常に重要です。
If you do a treatment and the person gets up,
もしあなたが治療をして、その人が立ち上がって、
and you see that their eyes are...
そしてあなたは彼の目が...
It's not over.
まだ終わっていません。
Do you understand what I mean?
私の言っていることがわかりますか？
This space here, but this amniotic cavity,
この空間、つまりこの羊膜腔は、
it has something around you, like that, you see, that's there.
あなたの周りに何かがある、ほら、そこにある。
it's very important to be able to restore this balance.
このバランスを取り戻すことができるのは非常に重要です。
The eye will be the expression of your imbalance in your zone B.
目はあなたのゾーンBの不均衡の表現となるでしょう。
And zone B is that.
そしてゾーンBとはこれです。
You see, this space around the embryo, like that.
ほら、胚の周りのこの空間、こんな風に。
Well, this space, in my practice, in my perception,
さて、この空間は、私の実践では、私の認識では、
is still there.
まだそこにあります。
Not in liquid form,
液体の形ではなく、
because water can be found in different states.
水はさまざまな状態で見つけることができるからです。
It can be found on an ice-like plane,
それは氷のような平面で見つけることができます、
a vapor-like,
蒸気のような、
there is still this space around
まだこの空間が周りにあります
and we feel it.
そして私たちはそれを感じます。
I can enter here, at some point, we will enter intimacy.
私はここに入ることができます、ある時点で、私たちは親密さに入ります。
I want to put it here.
私はここに入りたい。
And each one will have this space more or less large.
そして、それぞれが多かれ少なかれこの空間を持つことになります。
With radiations
放射線と共に
quite important because the heart
心臓はかなり重要なので
emits a magnetic radiation,
磁気放射を放出します。
it has been calculated, even verified,
それは計算され、検証さえされています。
up to 4, 5, 6 meters
4、5、6メートルまで
around you.
あなたの周りに。
Also in relation to that.
それにも関連しています。
It is important to understand, first of all, this relationship that exists between this amniotic cavity,
まず、この羊膜腔と目、そして
amniotic cavity, the eye, and
羊膜腔、目、そして
the entire ventricular system.
全脳室系との関係を理解することが重要です。
Because this is a ventricular system, and I tell you, the eye is an expansion
なぜなら、これは脳室系であり、私が言うように、目は
of the third ventricle.
第三脳室の拡張だからです。
But it already expands before the closure of the anterior neuropore, just before this closure.
しかし、それは前神経孔が閉じる前に、その閉鎖の直前にすでに拡張しています。
And we will see that there will be a whole genetic implication.
そして、遺伝的な関与が全体的にあることがわかるでしょう。
very interesting, with co-localizations on
非常に興味深いことに、
different impact zones,
異なる影響領域に共局在しています。
such as the same information on the hepatopancreatic level, for example,
例えば、肝膵臓レベルで同じ情報があるように、
with the same coding genes, cardiac and thyroid.
同じ遺伝子コード、心臓、甲状腺を持っています。
Diabetes will express itself on the eye.
糖尿病は目に現れます。
The heart will express itself on the eye.
心臓は目に現れます。
Organized level by the neural crest that we will review a little in the study of laterality,
側性化の研究で少し見直すことになる、臍帯稜によって組織化されたレベル、
of the organization of the median axis through this primitive median line.
この原始的な正中線を通じた正中軸の組織化です。